<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Anthony Ross' Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://yoursite.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://yoursite.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-13T19:51:15-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://yoursite.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Anthony Ross]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First Post!]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/blog/2014/01/08/my-first-post/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-08T21:40:28-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/blog/2014/01/08/my-first-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Happy January 13th everyone!  I&rsquo;m really excited today as I&rsquo;ve launched this blog using some wonderful Ruby on Rails gems.  Since this is my first post, I think I should explain where I am at today but also where I&rsquo;m coming from.</p>

<p>Learning programming has been an on &amp; off again relationship &ndash; one that started when I was 13 and has continued to rear it&rsquo;s head time and time again.  This time though, as I&rsquo;m anxiously approaching the daunting year that I turn 30 &ndash; I have finally conceded to my own intuition.</p>

<p>See back in High School, I coded and I coded hard.  I had 3 machines running Linux. I wrote a script that made my mom solve complex math problems before she could log onto the machine (she loved this &ndash; I swear.  I called it the &ldquo;logger logger&rdquo;), I had auto-responders on IRC before there was a bot to do that and I eventually made a program that enabled me to write plain text (in English) and it would spit out my Spanish homework.</p>

<p>However, at the age of 18 &ndash; I convinced myself that coding wasn&rsquo;t a &ldquo;creative endeavor&rdquo;.  That it wasn&rsquo;t going to be where I left my mark on the world and that I should try something else.  I went to college, studied business and eventually hung up my programming hat for a while.</p>

<p>After a series of mediocre jobs, none that really intrigued me or asked me to solve any real-world issues, I came back to programming with a new sense of purpose.  I didn&rsquo;t know what that purpose was, I just knew that I was underutilized in my job and therefore wanted to try my hand at developing again.  I&rsquo;m more experienced in life and in business, but more importantly I have a firm understanding of certain areas in the world that have gaps &ndash; some that I think I can help overcome.</p>

<p>In the end, my goal here is a bit selfish, that is to make a better me &ndash; one that involves a live and a career that makes me a forever student.  I’m the last person to claim to know everything and I think this future career in development fits that mindset, perfectly.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
